Guide to the Stanford University, Office of Chicano Affairs, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Office of Chicano Affairs, records
1967-1985
SC0291
Stanford University. Office of Chicano Affairs.
46.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - ATISBOS subscriptions (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ATISBOS correspondence, before 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chicano National Review (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chicano National Review (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National list of Chicano contracts in higher education (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Science and engineering, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stanford and the schools project (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Stanford article in Equal Opportunity Forum, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Budgets, Chicano Urban Studies 7-RBE-034 Bibliography, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Center for Chicano Research (SCCR) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - SCCR (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - SCCR fundraising group (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - SCCR visiting advisory committee (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - SCCR National Chicano Urban History Project (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Task Force of Cable Television (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Task Force for Undergraduate Study (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Report of Committee to Review Office of Chicano Affairs (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Report of Committee to Review (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - California Student Aid Information (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chicano Affairs Office - Annual Report, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Search Committee for the Assistant to the Provost Chicano Affairs (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Office Files, Search Committee for the Assistant to the Provost for Chicano Affairs (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Office Files, Search Committee for the Assistant to the Provost for Chicano Affairs (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Search for Assistant to the President for Chicano Affairs (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Resource pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Resignation request to S.J. Sanchez (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Search Committee, Advisor to the President on Chicano Affairs, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chicano Alumni Conference, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Chicano Alumi Association lists, 1969-1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Concilio de Asuntos Chicanos (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Computerized Data Base for Chicano Research, 1978 Nov 30, 1978 Dec 30 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Proposal, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - ATISBOS: General correspondence (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - El Informandor (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Luis G. Nogales files, 1969-1974
    Assistant to the President
    - The Mexican American: A Selected & Annotated Bibliography #1 First Edition (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - The Mexican American: A Selected & Annotated Bibliography #2 First Edition (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - The Mexican American: A Selected & Annotated Bibliography #3 First Edition (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Mexican American: A Selected & Annotated Bibliography #4 First Edition (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - The Mexican American: A Selected & Annotated Bibliography #5 First Edition (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - The Mexican American: A Selected & Annotated Bibliography I Second Edition (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The Mexican American: A Selected & Annotated Bibliography II Second Edition (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Mexican American: A Selected & Annotated Bibliography III Second Edition (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Mexican American: A Selected & Annotated Bibliography IV Second Edition (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Mexican American: A Selected & Annotated Bibliography V Second Edition (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - The Mexican American Bibliography First Edition Dr. JJJ (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Mexican American: 2nd Editon A Selected and Annotated Bibliography JJJ (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Chicano Studies Planning Grant Committee I, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Chicano Studies Planning Grant committee II, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Summer Institue in Chicano Affairs: Stanford University II, 1970 Summer (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Summer Institue in Chicano Affairs: Stanford University I, 1971 Summer (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Chicano Executive Committee Background Materials, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Education Development Center: Harvard Meeting of Undergraduate Officers, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Graduate recruitment (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The following documents (approximately dating from 1967-1973) were files of Luis G. Nogales when he was Assistant to the President
    - National Defense Student Loan Program - Manual, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - General correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - El Plan de Santa Barbara, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Human Relations Committee (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Medical School Minority Admissions Committee (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Native Americans (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Undergraduate Information, Circa 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Task Force I (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Task Force II (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - California Legislature Senate Committee on Education Members of the committee (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Chicano Council on Higher Education Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Chicano Orientation (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Communication Study Opportunities for Minority Group Members (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Human subjects (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Listing of fellowships, scholarships, and grants in-aid offer, to predoctoral students (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Medical School Program for Minority Students (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Mexican-American Seminar, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Mexican-American Seminar, Report to National Endowment, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Mexican-American Seminar, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - The Mex-Am Bibliography - Budget (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aids - Academic Council (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Alviso (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - MALDEF-Mexican American Legal Defense, Education and Funds (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Mexican-American-Organizations (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Minority/Chicano project (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Reports-See Also Princeton Files (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Chicano Fellows, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Chicano Library, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Chicano Library III, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Chicano Seminars, Richard Soto, Director, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Chicano Seminars, Richard Soto, Director, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Luis G. Nogales and Sal Sanchez files, 1972-1974
    - Chicano programs other schools, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Faculty recruitment (Arturo Islas), 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Faculty listings at colleges & universities, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Faculty recruitment, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - M.E.CH.A. (cont.), 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Sal Sanchez files, 1972-1974
    - Standford Soledad Teaching Project 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - U.S. 68 Course (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Faculty recruitment, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - End of Sal Sanchez, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - M.E.CH.A. budgets, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - SCOR project, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Annual reports, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - INTERIM CHICANO EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE, 1973-1974
    - Chronological file, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - General correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - General correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - General correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - CECILIA BURCIAGA, 1972-1977
    - M.E.CH.A. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Proposals and projects #2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Chronological file, 1976 Jan-Sep (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Chronological file, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Chicano community correspondence misc. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with departments - A-Econ (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with departments - Educ - Physics (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with departments - Poli Sci - Span (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with departments - Medicine (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Faculty recruitment - Lupe's File (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - COSS Subcommittee (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Chicano Executive Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Stanford library computer search on La Chicana (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - La Chicana - Mexican-American Women (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1976 Oct-1977 Apr (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Maria Baeza, 1973-1978
    - Humanities and Sciences (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Rationale to continue office of Chicano Affairs (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Review of literature pertaining to Chicanos in higher education (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Employment recruitment program (Phase I), 1978 Feb (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Minority Report (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Chronological file, 1978 Jan-1978 Oct (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - FERNANDO DE NECOCHEA, 1981-1984
    Assistant Provost and Advisor to the President for Chicano Affairs
    - Chronological file, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Chronological file, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Chronological file, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Chronological file, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Chronological file, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Subcommittee on distribution requirements (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Chronological file, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Chronological file, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Chronological file, 1982-1983 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Chronological file, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - files of various Assistants to the President
    - ESO Workshop-Action in Education (Box 18)
    - Beyond Sex Roles-Chicanisma (Box 18)
    - Colonization and the Mestiza, A Framework for Discrimination and the Chicana (Box 18)
    - Chicana Research and Learning Center (Box 18)
    - Sex Rols Issues of Minority Women (Box 18)
    - Strategies to Meet the Education Nees and Strengths of Minority Women (Box 18)
    - Sexual Stereotypes -Psychological and Cultural Survival (Box 18)
    - Women: New Voice of La Raza (Box 18)
    - Chicana Newspaper "Hijas de Cuahtemoc" (Box 18)
    - White Women's Liberation: The Oppressive Revolution (Box 18)
    - A Young Woman's Death: Would Health Rights Have Prevented It? (Box 18)
    - Minority Women and Higher Education #2 (Box 18)
    - Minority Women and Higher Education #3 (Box 18)
    - A Statistical Report on the Spanish Speaking Women in Higher Education (Box 18)
    - Women of Spanish Orign in the United States (Box 18)
    - Joint Committee on Legal Equality: Update on Legislative Round-up (Box 18)
    - The Chicana: A Bibliographic Study (Box 18)
    - Bibliography-TEP 401-Education and the Chicano (Box 18)
    - Bibliography-By Consuelo Nieto (Box 18)
    - Conac Converence - Queretao, Mexico (Box 18)
    - Santa Cruz Panel, 1975 Apr 26 (Box 18)
    - Pacro-Presno, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Women in the United States Panel, 1975 Apr 16 (Box 18)
    - National Institute on Access to Higher Education for the Mex-American (Box 18)
    - Universites correspondence, 1974 Aug-1976 Nov (Box 18)
    - Request, 1974 May 24-1977 May 24 (Box 18)
    - Fellowship, 1974-1976 (Box 18)
    - Affirmative Action Coordinators, 1972 Sep 12-1978 Jul 19 (Box 18)
    - Affirmative Action Office, 1972 Sep 7-1978 May 10 (Box 18)
    - External Affirmative Action, 1972 Sep 5-1977 Apr 4 (Box 18)
    - Research Associates, 1976 Mar 15-1978 Feb 14 (Box 18)
    - Staff Affirmative Action, 1975 Apr 7-1975 Jul 21 (Box 18)
    - Reports (Box 18)
    - Newsletters, articles, etc. (Box 18)
    - Other Affirmative Action Offices (Box 18)
    - CPPC, 1975-1976 Aug (Box 18)
    - Director of Student Employment-CPPC, 1972 Sep-1973 Jun (Box 18)
    - Ethinic theme housing, 1974 May-1975 Jul (Box 18)
    - Dean of Student-Presidential Education, 1974 Jan-1976 Apr (Box 18)
    - Cowell, Dean of Students, 1974 Aug-1976 Sep (Box 18)
    - Presidential Education - Dean of Students, 1976 (Box 18)
    - C.A.S.A. (Box 18)
    - Lulac (Box 18)
    - Mcoe (Massachuesetts Center of Occupational Education) (Box 18)
    - Nache (National Associaton of Chicano in Higher Education) (Box 18)
    - Mexican American Council for Economic Progress (Box 18)
    - Mexican-American Unity Council (Box 18)
    - Pamphlets (Box 18)
    - The Small Businessmen's Brotherhood (Box 18)
    - United Minority Business Enterpreneurs (Box 18)
    - Far West Laboratories (Box 18)
    - CONAC (El Congreso Nacional de Asuntos Colegiales - Pepe Barron) (Box 18)
    - Lopez-Bravo and Associates (Box 18)
    - Senate Committee on admissions policy (Box 18)
    - Medical center (Box 18)
    - Office general (Box 18)
    - Budget financial forecast (Box 18)
    - General Law School (Box 18)
    - Carlos Jackson (Box 18)
    - New Student Orientation - Dean of Students (Box 18)
    - Minority Parent Seminar - Dean of Students (Box 18)
    - CPCC (Box 18)
    - Bilingual & BABEL -Proposal for fellowships (Box 18)
    - Bilingual Fellowships - Funding sources (Box 18)
    - Fellowship - Funding source (Box 18)
    - Chicana Service Action Center (Box 18)
    - Chicana Colectiva (Box 18)
    - Chicana Journal (Box 18)
    - Concilio Mujeres (Box 18)
    - Minority Women Employment Program (Box 18)
    - Education of Women at Stanford (Box 18)
    - Stanford Chicana Research Project (Box 18)
    - Chicanas and Lupe Anguiano Correspondence (Box 18)
    - Chicano Graduation, 1977 (Box 18)
    - La Onda, 1975 Oct-1976 May (Box 18)
    - Chicano faculty, 1974-1976 Sep (Box 18)
    - Chicano orientation, 1974 Sep-1977 Feb (Box 18)
    - Cinco de Mayo, 1976 (Box 18)
    - Chicano library (Box 18)
    - Budget forecasts (Box 18)
    - Search Committee for the Assistant to the President, 1974 (Box 18)
    - President's office - general (Box 18)
    - Buckley Amendment (Box 18)
    - Ron Arroyo - Graduate Studies (Box 18)
    - Chicano Staff (Box 18)
    - DOSA - Office of Student Activites - Activities Advisory Search, 1975 (Box 18)
    - Personnel - General (Box 18)
    - Maria Schneider (Box 18)
    - Return of Indian as mascot (Box 18)
    - Native Americans (Box 18)
    - Provost's Senior Staff Meetings, 1977 (Box 18)
    - Lopez Collection (Box 18)
  - Financial Aid, 1974-1976 (Box 19)
  - CORRESPONDENCE (Box 19)
  - LETTERS AND TELEGRAMS (Box 19)
  - MEETINGS. PLANNING. LISTS (Box 19)
  - LOPEZ SCHOLARSHIP FUND (Box 19)
  - INVITATIONS (Box 19)
  - Applicants for Stone Position (Box 19)
  - Grievance--JM (Box 19)
  - Transfer Students (Box 19)
  - Affirmative Action (Box 19)
  - Activities Advisor Search, 1976-77 (Box 19)
  - Bing Nursery (Box 19)
  - TOMAS YBARRA FRAUSTO (Box 19)
  - PUBLIC EVENTS (Box 19)
  - PUBLIC RELATIONS (Box 19)
  - SCHNEIDER 'S REPLACEMENT (Box 19)
  - BILL STONE (Box 19)
  - FRED GLOVER'S REPLACEMENT (Box 19)
  - Academic Advisors (Box 19)
  - Admissions--Luis Lujan (Box 19)
  - Admissions -- Emily Canales (Box 19)
  - Admissions Office (Box 19)
  - Bechtel International Center (Box 19)
  - Minority Student Recruiting CPPC (Box 19)
  - Newsletter-CPPC (Box 19)
  - Committe on Services to Students, Oct 1975-June 1976 (Box 19)
  - Asian Americans (1971 Housing proposal) (Box 19)
  - Blacks 1974 Cultural Center Proposal (Box 19)
  - Chicano 1971 Chicano Housing Proposal (Box 19)
  - Native American (Box 19)
  - Manuscripts papers, articles, Sep 1974-Aug 1975 (Box 19)
  - Mexican American Bibliography, 1974 (Box 19)
  - Publications, June 1971-Feb. 1978 (Box 19)
  - Film, June 1969-June 1977 (Box 19)
  - El Mirlo Canta de Noticatlan, Oct. 1974-0ct. 1978 (Box 19)
  - Newspapers, Chicano, 1975 (Box 19)
  - Colleges and Universities, March 1974 - Jan. 1977 (Box 19)
  - United States Government Offices, Aug 1974-Sept. 1976 (Box 19)
  - CROW, Nov 1975-July 1979 (Box 19)
  - University of Washington, 1975 (Box 19)
  - Chicanas, May 75-June 1977 (Box 19)
  - Board of Directors Meetings, 1976 (Box 19)
  - United Stanford Employees, Aug 1974-Sept 1976 (Box 19)
  - Funding Sources, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Pre-Law, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Undergraduate Studies General, 1974 (Box 19)
  - Latin America (Box 19)
  - Carlos Arce--Seminar on Research Methodol ogy- -Stanford University, Nov 1977-0ec. 1978 (Box 19)
  - Kathy Zamora, July 1977-June 1978 (Box 19)
  - Board of Directors--Meetings, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Food Club Kit, 1976 (Box 19)
  - Publications, Urban Coalition, June 1974 -Nov. 1976 (Box 19)
  - Graduate Students Affairs, July 1974-Feb. 1978 (Box 19)
  - Galarza Reception, Nov. 1976 -May 1977 (Box 19)
  - FERNANDO DE NECOCHEA
    The following documents (dating from 1985) were files of FERNANDO DE NECOCHEA when he was Assistant Provost and Advisor to the President for Chicano Affairs
    - Committee documentation - Senate Committee on t he Relation Between The Hoover Institute and The Stanford Professoriate - 1985 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Commi ttee documentation - Senate Committee on the Relation Between The Hoover Institute and The Stanford Professoriate - 1985 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - XXIV Congreso del Instituto Internaciona l de Literatura Iberoamericana - 7/8-12/85 - documenta t ion (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - XXIV Congreso del Instituto lnternacional de Litera tu ra Iberoamericana - 7/8-12/85 - documentation (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Demographic Survey (Box 21, Folder 1-3)
      The following documents (dating from 1979) were files of MARIA BAEZA when she was Assistant to the President
    - Documents (approximately dating from 1978) from the files of MARIA BAEZA when she was Assistant to the President, related to personnel and affirmative ac ti on matters. (Box 22, Folder 1-3)
    - various chicano publications (working papers, bibliographies, short stories). (Box 22)
    - Files and papers presented at The XXIV Cong reso, Instituto Internacional de titeratura Iberoamericana, St anford University, 8- 12 July 1985 (Box 23)
    - Files and papers presented at The XXIV Congreso, Instituto Internacional de Literatura Iberoamericana, Stan ford University, 8-12 July 1985 (Box 24)
    - Draft documents f or the final report of the Senate Commi ttee on the Re lat ion between t he lIoover Ins titution and Stanford Pro fessori ate (SCRHI P) (Box 25)
    - Documents 1 through 205 and supporting files for the Committee on the Relation between the Hoover Ins t itution and Stanford Professoriate (SCRHIP) (Box 26)